Guide to the Board of Trustees Reference Collection, 1941-2002 UA.01.11.0007
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Board of Trustees Reference collection
1941 - 2002
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. University Archives
UA.01.11.0007
2 Linear Feet
The Duke University Board of Trustees is the administrative decision-making body that oversees the planning and direction of the University. The Board of Trustees Reference Collection is mainly comprised of clippings and lists of Board members. English.
2000 Items
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
The majority of the collection was not created by the Board of Trustees and does not comprise the Board of Trustees Records, and so is open for use. See paragraph below for restrictions on Board of Trustees Records, such as minutes.
Records of the University's Board of Trustees which have been in existence for at least fifty years are available for scholarly research with the permission of the University Archivist. Access to records which have been in existence for less than fifty years shall be granted only by special permission, in writing, from the Board of Trustees.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Provenance
The Board of Trustees Reference Collection was compiled by University Archives staff from a variety of sources.
Historical Note
The Duke University Board of Trustees is the administrative decision-making body that oversees the planning and direction of the University. The Board consists of 36 members. More information about the Board can be found at the University Secretary's website at: http://www.duke.edu/web/ous/
Collection Overview
The Board of Trustees Reference Collection is mainly comprised of clippings and lists of Board members. The first series, Duke University, features clippings on a number of Duke events and issues that affected the Board. The second series, Board of Trustees, contains lists of members, press reports, citations, and the Trustee Manual.
Related Material
Board of Trustees Records
Duke University Archives
Duke University -- Finance; Duke University -- History; Duke University -- Students; Duke University. Board of Trustees; Duke University -- Faculty; Duke University -- Administration; Duke University. University Archives
- Duke University, 1941-1983
  Scope and Contents note
  The Duke University series contains clipping files kept by the Duke Endowment. These files relate to major issues faced by the trustees. The materials are arranged in alphabetical order.
  - 1950, 1960-1964 (Box 1)
  - 1965-1967 (Box 1)
  - 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - 1970-1972, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Demonstrations, 1968-February 1969, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Desegregation, 1961-1963 (Box 1)
  - Durham Herald Sun, May 25, 1941 (copy) (Box 1)
  - Hollis Edens--Inauguration, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Edens's Resignation/Edens-Gross Affair/Hart Selection, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Douglas M. Knight--Selection and Inauguration, 1961-1963 (Box 1)
  - Douglas M. Knight--Resignation, 1969 (Box 1)
  - W. R. Perkins Library, 1966-1970 (Box 1)
  - Terry Sanford--Inauguration, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Trustees, circa 1961-1971 (Box 1)
  - Trustees, circa 1974-1983 (Box 1)
- Board of Trustees, 1960-2002
  The Board of Trustees series was compiled by the University Archives and primarily contains lists of members and press clippings about the Board.
  - Addresses, circa 1964-1992 (Box 2)
  - Chairmen from 1892 to 2002 (Box 2)
  - Citations, 1981-1989 (Box 2)
  - Lists of Members of Board of Trustees from 1839 to 1992 (Box 2)
  - Meetings--Press Reports
    - 1960-1969 (Box 2)
    - December 1973-1974 (Box 2)
    - 1975-1979 (Box 2)
    - 1980-June 1985 (Box 2)
    - July 1985-June 1990 (Box 2)
    - July 1990-June 1992 (Box 2)
    - July 1992-June 1993 (Box 2)
    - October 1993-December 1993 (Box 2)
    - 1994-1998 (Box 2)
    - 1998-2001 (Box 2)
  - Trustee Manual, circa 1980 (Box 2)
  - Young Trustees, circa 1977-2005 (Box 2)
  - RESTRICTED: Divestment (from minutes), circa 1980s (Box Duke Archives Restricted 2 of 2)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Records of the University's Board of Trustees which have been in existence for at least fifty years are available for scholarly research with the permission of the University Archivist. Access to records which have been in existence for less than fifty years shall be granted only by special permission, in writing, from the Board of Trustees.